Emiliano Caballero Beisso

Montevideo, Uruguay (GMT-3)



emiliano.caballero.beisso@gmail.com



091612225



linkedin.com/in/emiliano-caballero-beisso



https://em1h.github.io/react-portfolio/

Summary

+2 years experience Front-end Developer and advanced student of Computer Engineering. Currently working for an international software factory called Codigo del Sur in which we provide digital solutions for customers mainly from the US. Participated in different industry contexts such as e-commerce products, milk production industry, video streaming and drones, forming part of small and large teams ranging from 3 to 30 members.

Passionate about React and CSS, with a focus on pixel perfection, responsiveness, and UX.

I love working on projects that involve modern technologies and I enjoy staying up-to-date with the latest features released and best practices in front-end development.

Skills: React, TypeScript, JavaScript, ES6, Redux, Redux-Saga, CSS, styled-components, Material-UI, Sass, Storybook, Express is, Sequelize, Jest, TailwindCSS, Algorithms, Data Structures. Past: backend, PHP, Java, PostgreSQL, jQuery.

English / Español

Experience



Front-end Developer

CodigoDelSur

Dec 2021 - Present (1 year 4 months)

Front-End for several web app platforms for "One - Milc group" (milcgroup.com/one) giving tech solutions in the dairy industry.

- New features and web sections by turning Figma and Zeplin boards into React components.
- Gave demo presentations to the client, showcasing what was completed in the last sprints.
- Visual enhancements improving the user interface and user experience by converting layouts into responsive ones.
- Improved readability, functionality, and maintainability of the code by applying SOLID principles under React.
- Migrated and refactored legacy project code that was based on JSP and JavaScript vanilla into React.
- Improved the development time of the team by creating new reusable components and refactoring old ones.
- Production support.

[React.js / TypeScript / JavaScript vanilla / Redux / CSS / styled-components / Express.js / Sequelize]

Front-end for PacPost (pacpost.live/), a multifunctional video streaming and video conferencing platform that allows users to collaborate on video streams in real time.

- Focused on the UI optimization, streaming watermarking, and protection of the code by using obfuscation tools and anti-tampering techniques.
- Improved readability, functionality, and performance by refactoring existing components. [ReactJS / TypeScript / CSS / Twilio]

Front-end for a web app platform Ware (ware.ai/) that allows to automate and digitize warehouses with inventory counting drones.

- Problem solving by following the client's demands, doing what's necessary to meet the project's
- Software maintenance and bug fixing. [ReactJS / Redux-Saga / TypeScript / SASS]

POC for DJI conference:

Collaborated in the front end for building a Proof-of-Concept to be exhibited in the annual commercial drone conference "Airworks 2022". Worked using Vue.js, involving some Google maps integration with adding some drawing features and interactions with the drone

Full-stack Developer

Niveltic

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021 (1 year 3 months)

eCommerce for a recognized market from Argentina called La Anonima (laanonima.com.ar/), and other smaller sites.

Front-end: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS.

Back-end: PHP, PostgreSQL

Education



Universidad de la República

Computer Engineering, Advanced student - 3rd/4th grade

Aug 2014 - Jan 2020

Relevant topics:

Algorithms - Data Structures - Operating Systems - Computer Networking - Software Engineering -

Databases - Logic - Computer Architecture - a lot of Maths

Skills

React.is • TypeScript • CSS • ES6 • Redux • styled-components • Storybooks • JavaScript • Express.js • Sequelize.js